One man alone understood the savagery of the
early American west from both sides.
Ulzana's Raid is a western film directed by Robert Aldrich.
After fierce war chief Ulzana and a small war party jump the reservation bent on murder and
terror, an inexperienced young lieutenant is assigned to track him down.
McIntosh, played by Burt Lancaster.
Lt. Garnett DeBuin, played by Bruce Davison.
Ke-Ni-Tay, played by Jorge Luke.
Sergeant, played by Richard Jaeckel.
Ulzana, played by Joaquín Martínez.
Captain Gates, played by Lloyd Bochner.
Ulzana's Raid is a 1972 American revisionist Western film starring Burt
Lancaster, Richard Jaeckel, Bruce Davison, and Joaquin Martinez.
Filmed on location in Arizona, it was directed by Robert
Aldrich based on a script by Alan Sharp.
It portrays a brutal raid by Chiricahua Apaches
against American settlers in 1880s Arizona.
The film explores themes of ambush, indian territory,
apache nation, lieutenant, rape victim.